Guide to the Matthew Vassar Papers, 1730-1975
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series III. Matthew Vassar and Company, Brewers
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 26 Oct 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.602)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 31 Oct 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.603)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 1 Nov 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.604)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sirs, 2 Nov 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.605)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Mr. J.K. Wing, 4 Nov 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.606)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to H. Edwards, 11 Nov 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.607)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 15 Nov 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.608)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Gentlemen, 23 Nov 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.609)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 28 Nov 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.610)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Gentlemen, 1 Dec 1843; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.611)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 12 Jan 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.612)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 17 Jan 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.613)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 26 Mar 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.614)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 27 Mar 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 20.615)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 5 Apr 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.616)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 11 Apr 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.617)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 2 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.618)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar, Co. to Matthew Vassar, 3 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.619)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 5 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.620)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 11 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.621)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 16 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.622)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 18 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.623)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 21 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.624)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 22 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.625)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 24 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.626)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 25 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.627)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 29 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.628)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 31 Oct 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.629)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 1 Nov 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.630)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 3 Nov 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.631)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 14 Nov 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.632)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 15 Nov 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.633)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to [James?], [Dec?] 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.634)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 6 Nov 1845; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.635)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 14 Nov 1845; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.636)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 21 Oct 1843 or 21 Oct 1845; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.637)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 7 Jan 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.638)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 9 Jan 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.639)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 10 Jan 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.640)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 12 Jan 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.641)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 23 Jan 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.642)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 15 Sep 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.643)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 5 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.644)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 7 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.645)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 14 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.646)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 20 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.647)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 23 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.648)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 23 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.649)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 27 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.650)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 29 Oct 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.651)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 4 Nov 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.652)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 5 Nov 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.653)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 11 Nov 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.654)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 12 Oct 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.655)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 26 Oct 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.656)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 27 Oct 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.657)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 28 Oct 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.658)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 28 Oct 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.659)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear [Sirs?], 30 Oct 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 21.660)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 16 Nov 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.661)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Jr., 17 Nov 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.662)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 7 Dec 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.663)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 8 Dec 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.664)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sirs, 9 Dec 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.665)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 16 Dec 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.666)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sirs, 20 Dec 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.667)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 21 Dec 1847; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.668)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 26 Jan 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.669)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to James Vassar, Jr., 27 Jan 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.670)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sirs, 1 Feb 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.671)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to James Vassar c/o Vassar, Co., 2 Feb 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.672)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 4 Feb 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.673)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 10 Feb 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.674)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 14 Sep 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.675)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 24 Sep 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.676)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 25 Sep 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.677)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 27 Sep 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.678)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 12 Oct 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.679)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 17 Oct 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.680)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 25 Oct 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.681)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 3 Nov 1848; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.682)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Nephew, 9 Aug 1849; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.683)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sirs, 2 Oct 1849; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.684)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Gentlemen, 4 Oct 1849; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.685)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver H. Booth, 2 Nov 1849; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.686)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar, Co., 19 Nov 1849; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.687)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver [Booth?], 3 Dec 1849; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.688)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sirs, 24 Dec 1849; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.689)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 8 Feb 1850; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.690)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 24 Dec 1850; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.691)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 25 Dec 1850; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.692)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to [Oliver Booth], 15 Jan 1851; (1 letter, 1 transcript) (Folder 23.905)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver, 3 Oct 1851; (1 letter) (Folder 23.710)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 12 Nov 1851; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.693)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Nephew, 27 Nov 1851; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.694)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar, Co., 31 Jan 1852; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.695)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar Co., 16 Aug 1852; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.696)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 24 Nov 1852; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.697)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver, 27 Dec 1852; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.698)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sirs, 11 Feb 1853; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.699)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Matthew Vassar, Co., 15 Apr 1853; (1 letter)** (Folder 22.700)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Nephew, 23 Jun 1853; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.701)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, 30 Sep 1853; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.702)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver H. Booth, 16 Dec 1853; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.703)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver, 20 Dec 1853; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.704)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Nephew, 1854; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.705)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver, 2 Mar 1855; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.706)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to A.R. Booth, 13 Mar 1855; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.707)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver, 13 Mar 1855; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.708)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to A.R. Booth, 2 May 1856; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.709)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Oliver H. Booth, 4 Sep 1863; (1 letter)** (Folder 23.711)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: [Law?], J. to Matthew Vassar, Co., undated; (1 letter)*** (Folder 14.712)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Parser, Thomas to Vassar, undated; (1 letter)*** (Folder 14.713)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Dear Sir, undated; (1 letter)*** (Folder 14.714)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., financial papers: Statement of Affairs, 17 Aug 1829; (1 item) (Folder 25.715 (Oversize))
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Articles of Agreement- Brewery Wages, [1832?]; (1 item)** (Folder 14.716)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Bills, notes, 1816-1839; (16 items)** (Folder 14.717)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Bills, notes, 1842-1879; (15 items)** (Folder 14.718)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Bills - miscellaneous (Folder 14.719)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Account with John Guy Vassar, 1847; (2 sheets)** (Folder 14.720)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Account with Matthew Vassar, 1835-1837, 1842-1843; (3 items)** (Folder 14.721)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Inventory of debts, 21 Jul 1832; (1 item) (Folder 14.722)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., Financial papers: Tax receipts, 1838, 1839; (2 items)** (Folder 14.723)
  - Lansingburgh Brewery: Papers concerning Brewery, Malthouse in Lansingburgh, undated; (8 items) (Folder 14.724)
  - "Patent for Improvement in Vent Plugs,", undated; (1 item) (Folder 25.725 (Oversize))
  - Patents, undated; (8 sheets of photocopies, printed materials) (Folder 25.726 (Oversize))
  - Old Vassar Brewery Property Map, Jul 1834; (25.25 x 14.75 in) (Mapcase Drawer 7 - Folder 49.30 (Oversize))
  - Photograph of a print of M. Vassar & Co. Brewery, undated (Folder 14.907)
  - Watercolor print of M. Vassar and Co. Brewery by Henry Whinfield, 1837; (1 framed item) (Framed Storage 1.5)
- Series IV. Property and Financial Papers - Personal and Business
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Memorandum, deed No.1, [31?] Dec 1831; (2 items) (Folder 24.727 (Oversize))
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Deeds No.2 - No.4, [31?] Dec 1831; (3 items) (Folder 24.728 (Oversize))
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Deeds A, [31?] Dec 1831 (Folder 24.729 (Oversize))
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Deeds B, [31?] Dec 1831 (Folder 24.730 (Oversize))
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Deeds C, F, G, [31?] Dec 1831 (Folder 24.731 (Oversize))
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Deeds H, I (does not match mem), [31?] Dec 1831 (Folder 24.732 (Oversize))
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Deeds J-Milbank affair, [31?] Dec 1831 (Folder 24.733 (Oversize))
  - Deeds in chest: Inventory, Accompanying Deeds: Deeds M, N, P, [31?] Dec 1831 (Folder 24.734 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1813-1818 (Folder 24.735 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1831-1829 (Folder 24.736 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 20 Feb 1833 - Aug 1833 (Folder 24.737 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 20 Aug 1833 - Nov 1833 (Folder 24.738 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1834 - Aug 1835 (Folder 24.739 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, Sep 1835 - Aug 1836 (Folder 24.740 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1837-1841 (Folder 26.741 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1842-1844 (Folder 26.742 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1845 (Folder 26.743 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1846 - Dec 1847 (Folder 26.744 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, Dec 1847 - 1853 (Folder 26.745 (Oversize))
  - Deeds, 1854-1864 (Folder 26.746 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1730 (Folder 26.747 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1769 - 31 Mar 1786 (Folder 26.748 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1 Apr 1786 - 1800 (Folder 26.749 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1801-1806 (Folder 26.750 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1808-1814 (Folder 26.751 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1817 (Folder 26.752 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1825-1832 (Folder 26.753 (Oversize))
  - Deeds pertaining to properties owned by Matthew Vassar, 1833-1855 (Folder 26.754 (Oversize))
  - Real Estate: Illinois, seeking property (folder 1 of 2), (10 items) (Folder 27.755)
  - Real Estate: Illinois, seeking property (folder 2 of 2), (1 item) (Folder 27.756)
  - Real Estate: Illinois, Michigan deeds, (3 items) (Folder 26.757 (Oversize))
  - Real Estate: Michigan-legal documents, (3 items) (Folder 27.758)
  - Real Estate: Plat map of Vassar Michigan, (1 item) (Folder 26.759 (Oversize))
  - Real Estate: Michigan accounts, (6 items) (Folder 27.760)
  - Real Estate: Michigan miscellaneous undated material, (5 items) (Folder 27.761)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 1 of 13), (9 items) (Folder 27.762)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 2 of 13), (12 items) (Folder 27.763)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 3 of 13), (14 items) (Folder 27.764)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 4 of 13), (14 items) (Folder 27.765)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 5 of 13), (10 items) (Folder 27.766)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 6 of 13), (13 items) (Folder 27.767)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 7 of 13), (11 items) (Folder 27.768)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 8 of 13), (9 items) (Folder 27.769)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 9 of 13), (12 items) (Folder 27.770)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 10 of 13), (11 items) (Folder 27.771)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 11 of 13), (8 items) (Folder 27.772)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 12 of 13), (11 items) (Folder 27.773)
  - Real Estate: Michigan correspondence etc.(folder 13 of 13), (11 items) (Folder 27.774)
  - Real Estate: Poughkeepsie, property held and accounts, (2 items) (Folder 27.775)
  - Real Estate:Record Lots of Vassar, Co. sold Sundry, Parsons, [1872?]; (1 ledger book) (Folder 28.776)
  - "Map of Land containing a quarry adjoining Plank Rd. to Stormville...", (1 item) (Folder 25.777 (Oversize))
  - Map of Poughkeepsie, surveyed by J. C. Sidney, published by M. Dripps, undated; (1 framed item) (Framed Storage 2.8 (Item 778))
  - Financial Agreements, 1819-1826; (4 items) (Folder 27.779)
  - Financial Agreements, 1834-1835; (7 items) (Folder 27.780)
  - Financial Agreements, 1840-1843; (3 items) (Folder 27.781)
  - Financial Agreements, 1849-1853; (7 items) (Folder 27.782)
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 1 of 11), 1815 - 27 Apr 1819; (3 items) (Folder 26.783 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 2 of 11), 1 Sep 1819 - 15 Mar 1823; (5 items) (Folder 26.784 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 3 of 11), 27 Oct 1828 - 19 Aug 1829; (3 items) (Folder 26.785 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 4 of 11), 19 Aug 1829; (4 items) (Folder 26.786 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 5 of 11), 23 Oct 1829 - 2 May 1831; (4 items) (Folder 26.787 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 6 of 11), 31 Aug 1831- 20 Aug 1833; (4 items) (Folder 29.788 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 7 of 11), 20 Aug 1833 - 1 Oct 1835; (4 items) (Folder 29.789 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 8 of 11), 1 Oct 1835 - 30 Apr 1836; (4 items) (Folder 29.790 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 9 of 11), 30 Apr 1836 - 31 Aug 1836; (4 items) (Folder 29.791 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 10 of 11), 1 May 1837 - 17 Apr 1841; (3 items) (Folder 29.792 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages (folder 11 of 11), 1 Jun 1853 - 1 Apr 1867; (3 items) (Folder 29.793 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages: Nelson Rider property (folder 1 of 3), (4 items) (Folder 29.794 (Oversize))
  - Bonds, Mortgages: Nelson Rider property (folder 2 of 3), (4 items) (Folder 27.795)
  - Bonds, Mortgages: Nelson Rider property (folder 3 of 3), (6 items) (Folder 27.796)
  - Leases (by, from), 1817-1858; (3 items) (Folder 29.797 (Oversize))
  - Leases (by, from), 1859-1865; (5 items) (Folder 29.798 (Oversize))
  - Stocks, (12 items) (Folder 30.799)
  - Stocks - Whaling Cos., (5 items) (Folder 30.800)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts:Farmers, Manufacturer's National Bank, 1868; (1 bank book) (Folder 30.801)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks, Mar-Jun 1860; (2 envelopes) (Folder 30.802)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks, 31 Aug 1861 - Nov 1861; (2 envelopes) (Folder 30.803)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks, Dec 1861 - Jan 1862; (1 envelope) (Folder 30.804)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks Nos. 193-209, 3 Aug 1867 - 29 Oct 1867; (1 envelope) (Folder 30.805)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks Nos. 210-231, 1 Nov 1867 - 11 Dec 1867; (1 envelope) (Folder 30.806)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks Nos. 232-256, 13 Dec 1867 -13 Jan 1868; (1 envelope) (Folder 30.807)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks Nos. 257-277, 14 Jan 1868 - 30 Mar 1868; (1 envelope) (Folder 30.808)
  - Checks, Bank Accounts: Checks Nos. 278-308, 1 Apr 1868 - 19 Jun 1868; (2 envelopes) (Folder 30.809)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Statement of M. Vassar's affairs, 1 Mar 1831; (1 item) (Folder 30.810)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: European trip 1845 - Expense account, (1 item)* (Folder 30.811)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers, (12 items) (Folder 30.812)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Bills, (10 items) (Folder 30.813)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Government bond, State of Wisconsin, (1 item) (Folder 30.814)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Insurance Certificate, (1 item) (Folder 31.815)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Promissory notes, 1810-1867; (10 items) (Folder 31.816)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Notes, considered bad debts, (20 items) (Folder 31.817)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Income, tax information, 1848, 1866; (2 items) (Folder 31.818)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers: Ledger book, 1850-1866; (1 item) (Folder 32.819)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Legal documents (folder 1 of 2), (4 items) (Folder 29.820 (Oversize))
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Legal documents (folder 2 of 2), (4 items) (Folder 29.821 (Oversize))
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Estate papers, 1841-1843; (9 items) (Folder 31.822)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Estate papers, 1843-1844; (8 items) (Folder 31.823)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Estate papers, 1844-1855; (7 items) (Folder 31.824)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Estate papers, 1861, 1869; (6 items) (Folder 31.825)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Undated material, (9 items) (Folder 31.826)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Accounts for farm, brickyard, 1842-1843; (6 items) (Folder 31.827)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: In account with Matthew Vassar, 1852-1861; (1 item) (Folder 31.828)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Notes of exchange, checks, (2 envelopes) (Folder 31.829)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Checks (folder 1 of 3), (1 envelope) (Folder 31.830)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Checks (folder 2 of 3), (1 envelope) (Folder 31.831)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Checks (folder 3 of 3), (1 envelope) (Folder 31.832)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Drafts, (3 items) (Folder 31.833)
  - Estate of Charles Vassar, Executor: Funeral bills, (6 items) (Folder 31.834)
  - Estate of George Belton, Executor: Executor, George Belton Estate (folder 1 of 2), (5 items) (Folder 31.835)
  - Estate of George Belton, Executor: Executor, George Belton Estate (folder 2 of 2), (5 items) (Folder 31.836)
  - Matthew Vassar's Wills, and note of amendment, 8 Jan 1868; (3 items) (Folder 31.837)
  - Matthew Vassar's Wills, 3 Feb 1868; (2 copies of 1 item) (Folder 31.838)
  - Matthew Vassar's Wills, 3 Feb 1868; (1 item) (Folder 31.839)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Journal of estate, (1 volume) (Folder 28.840)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Index to Estate Ledger, (1 volume) (Folder 28.841)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Estate Ledger, (1 volume) (Folder 33.842)